The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Ok then, let's start with problems.
教授：好的，让我们开始讨论问题。
And as we find concept issues, we'll get to concept issues.
当我们发现概念问题时，我们将涉及概念问题。
So, we talked about shortest-path,
因此，我们谈到了最短路径，
but we talked about shortest-path
但是我们谈到了最短路径
in a very odd way, right?
以一种非常奇怪的方式，对吗？
I'm a coder.
我是编码员。
So for me I'm used to, all right I go to one of these lectures,
所以对于我来说，我习惯了，去参加这些讲座之一，
I hear a problem, then I get out of the lecture
我听到一个问题，然后离开了讲座
with an algorithm and the running time, right?
有算法和运行时间，对吗？
This time we got out of the lecture
这次我们离开了讲座
with no algorithm and no running time.
没有算法，也没有运行时间。
So, what's the point?
那么，有什么意义呢？
The point is that we learned some analysis tricks
关键是我们学到了一些分析技巧
that we can use for any shortest-path algorithm.
我们可以将其用于任何最短路径算法。
And the advantage of knowing that-- by the way too easy
知道这一点的好处-太容易了
to forget, at least until you see the first real
忘记，至少直到看到第一个真实
algorithms-- if you know that, if you
算法-如果您知道，如果您
have to modify an algorithm, you can still use the same analysis
必须修改算法，仍然可以使用相同的分析
to prove that your new algorithm is going to be correct
证明您的新算法是正确的
and that it's going to be fast.
而且将会很快。
They're really nice tools to have,
它们是非常好的工具，
especially if you have to do that on a problem set
特别是如果您必须在问题集上这样做
or on an interview, or who knows, maybe even on a quiz.
或面试，或谁知道，甚至是测验。
We'll see if that happens or not.
我们将看看是否发生这种情况。
We didn't talk about any shortest-path algorithms.
我们没有谈论任何最短路径算法。
So, we're not going to assume shortest-path algorithms.
因此，我们不会采用最短路径算法。
Instead we're going to use them as if we had them.
相反，我们将像使用它们一样使用它们。
No, wait.
不，等等
I don't like that.
我不喜欢
That's kind of annoying.
真烦人。
Let's not do that.
我们不要那样做。
Let's do something else.
让我们做点别的。
We didn't talk about the shortest-path algorithm
我们没有谈论最短路径算法
in lecture.
在演讲中。
Let's build one right now, how about that?
让我们现在建立一个，那怎么样？
Let's turn to the graph.
我们来看一下图。
Vertices and edges, right?
顶点和边缘，对吗？
Let's see if I can make this work.
让我们看看我是否可以完成这项工作。
Suppose we have a graph.
假设我们有一个图。
We have V vertices, E edges and all the edges
我们有V个顶点，E个边和所有边
have a weight that's non-negative.
权重为非负数。
Sorry, let's make it positive just to make things easy.
抱歉，为了让事情变得简单，让我们积极向上。
It's smaller than W, so it's not too big.
它比W小，所以不是太大。
And they're all integers.
它们都是整数。
Go.
走。
There's brute-force, OK.
蛮力的，行。
So, brute-force would mean what?
那么，蛮力意味着什么？
Enumerate all the paths?
列举所有路径？
OK.
好。
Let's go over something a little bit better.
让我们来看一些更好的东西。
Does anyone remember the algorithm
有人记得算法吗
that was taught in class?
在课堂上教的？
The structure?
结构？
No.
没有。
Klaus mentioned Dijkstra and mentioned Bellman-Ford.
克劳斯提到了迪克斯特拉，并提到了贝尔曼·福特。
Let's write them up here.
让我们在这里写下它们。
And they gave us the running times,
他们给了我们跑步时间，
which we'll try to remember in a bit.
我们会尽力记住这一点。
But, we don't know algorithms, so no Dijkstra, no Bellman-Ford
但是，我们不知道算法，所以没有Dijkstra，没有Bellman-Ford
for us.
为了我们。
What do we know?
我们知道什么？
Let's start with a simpler case.
让我们从一个简单的案例开始。
What if there are no weights here.
如果这里没有重量怎么办。
What if the graph looked like this.
如果图形看起来像这样呢？
You're making my life hard.
你让我的生活很难。
Like this.
像这样。
No costs.
没有费用
All the edges have the same costs.
所有边缘的成本相同。
What would we do to solve the problem?
我们将如何解决该问题？
Say we want the shortest path from A to E.
假设我们想要从A到E的最短路径。
AUDIENCE: BFS.
观众：BFS。
PROFESSOR: BFS.
教授：BFS。
How's everyone feeling about BFS?
每个人对BFS的感觉如何？
What does BFS do, really quickly?
BFS真的可以做什么？
How do you run BFS?
您如何运行BFS？
AUDIENCE: Take a starting node and then you
听众：以一个起始节点然后
can search all it's neighbors.
可以搜索所有邻居。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Pick a starting node.
选择一个起始节点。
Then, look at its neighbors?
然后，看看它的邻居？
AUDIENCE: And then you enter it through each of its neighbors
听众：然后您通过它的每个邻居输入它
to find its neighbors and so forth.
寻找邻居等等。
PROFESSOR: Sounds an awful lot like BFS.
教授：听起来很像BFS。
What's the difference between them?
它们之间有什么区别？
AUDIENCE: Well, you go through all of these neighbors
听众：好吧，你经历了所有这些邻居
before you start going through any of it.
在您开始进行任何操作之前。
I mean, you go through all As neighbors
我的意思是，你经历了所有的邻居
before you take a neighbor and go
在你带邻居去之前
through all of its neighbors.
通过它的所有邻居。
PROFESSOR: Ok, that's the difference.
教授：好的，就是这样。
And it makes a huge difference as we've
就像我们已经
seen in topological sorting last time.
上次在拓扑排序中看到的。
So we have a list and we're going
所以我们有一个清单，我们要去
to use it to keep track of the nodes that we need to visit.
使用它来跟踪我们需要访问的节点。
We start with A. We numerate all of As neighbors.
我们从A开始。我们对所有As邻居进行计数。
And the ones that haven't been seen
还有那些没被看到的
get stuck at the end of the list.
卡在列表的末尾。
A, B, C. A is out of the list.
A，B，C。A不在列表中。
Then we take out the first node from the list, B in this case.
然后我们从列表中取出第一个节点，在这种情况下为B。
We numerate all its neighbors, A, C, D, E. Out of all these,
我们对所有邻居A，C，D，E进行计数。
we take the neighbors that we haven't seen
我们带走了我们未曾见过的邻居
and we put them at the end of the list.
然后将它们放在列表的末尾。
take out C, we look at its neighbors.
取出C，我们看一下它的邻居。
We've seen them.
我们已经看到了。
We take out D, we look at his neighbors.
我们拿出D，我们看着他的邻居。
We've seen them.
我们已经看到了。
We take out E, we look at all its neighbors.
我们取出E，然后看它的所有邻居。
We've seen them.
我们已经看到了。
So this is BFS.
这就是BFS。
BFS has this concept of levels.
BFS具有这种级别的概念。
And another way to look at levels is, if you start at A,
看水平的另一种方法是，如果您从A开始，
and you draw a circus of radius one,
然后画一个半径为一的马戏团
it's going to have all the nodes that are distance 1 from 8.
它将具有与8的距离为1的所有节点。
Right?
对？
Exactly one edge.
恰好一个边缘。
Then you draw a circus of radius 2
然后画一个半径为2的马戏团
and you get all the nodes that you can reach in two edges.
然后得到两个边缘都可以到达的所有节点。
And BFS calls these circles levels.
BFS称之为这些圈子级别。
A is at level 0.
A处于0级。
This is level 1.
这是1级。
This is level 2.
这是2级。
If you look at this list and you write down the levels,
如果您查看此列表并写下级别，
you have 0, 1, 1, 2, 2.
您有0、1、1、2、2。
If you had another node out here, say F,
如果您还有另一个节点，请说F，
this would be discovered when we get
这将在我们得到时被发现
to D. It would go all the way here at the end,
到D。最后会一直到这里，
and this is level 3.
这是3级
In BFS the levels are always increasing.
在BFS中，水平始终在增加。
If you keep track of parent pointers,
如果您跟踪父指针，
the parent pointer of a node, at some level,
在某种程度上，节点的父指针
will always point to a node at the previous level.
将始终指向上一级的节点。
So, in BFS we get the shortest paths in terms of edge count.
因此，在BFS中，就边缘计数而言，我们获得了最短的路径。
Make sense?
说得通？
This is a recall, right?
这是召回吧？
It is not new stuff.
这不是新东西。
Everyone happy with it?
每个人都满意吗？
If it wouldn't have costs, we could
如果没有成本，我们可以
use BFS to compute shortest paths.
使用BFS计算最短路径。
But, we have costs.
但是，我们有成本。
How do we deal with that?
我们该如何处理？
Intuitively, I'd like to make BFS go across this edge
凭直觉，我想让BFS跨越这一边缘
faster than it would go across the edge.
快过边缘。
If I could do that, if this guy could get stuck in the queue
如果我能做到的话，如果这个人可能陷入困境
before this guy, I would be happy.
在这家伙之前，我会很高兴。
Intuitively, that's what I'd like to do.
凭直觉，这就是我想要做的。
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Sort before adding?
听众：添加之前先排序？
PROFESSOR: Sort--
教授：排序-
AUDIENCE: Sort your neighbors sorts.
听众：对邻居排序。
PROFESSOR: Sort?
教授：排序？
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: What if you kept track of it in a menu?
听众：如果您在菜单中跟踪它怎么办？
Kept track of your queue as a priority queue.
将队列保留为优先队列。
PROFESSOR: Congratulations.
教授：恭喜。
You deserve a Turing Award.
您应得图灵奖。
You have discovered Dijkstra.
您已找到Dijkstra。
OK, let's go for something simpler.
好吧，让我们去简单一些。
I just say this is Dijkstra.
我只是说这是Dijkstra。
We'll talk about it in lecture on Tuesday.
我们将在星期二的讲座中谈论它。
Very good.
很好。
AUDIENCE: Like, have an adjacency list
听众：喜欢，有一个邻接表
and, I think using what he said.
而且，我想使用他的话。
Just sort it by cost--
只需按成本排序-
PROFESSOR: OK, let's see how this would work.
教授：好的，让我们看看这将如何工作。
We have A, and we're pulling A out of the list.
我们有A，并且正在将A从列表中拉出。
And we see its neighbors are C and B. Right?
我们看到它的邻居是C和B。对吗？
The distance to C is 2.
到C的距离是2。
The distance to B is 4.
到B的距离是4。
So we start with A. Does this mean
所以我们从A开始。这是否意味着
that I'm going to put in B before C?
我要在B之前放在C之前？
I'm going to put in C and then B?
我要先输入C然后再输入B？
AUDIENCE: No, it doesn't really matter
听众：不，没关系
because at the end you just sort the part.
因为最后您只需要对零件进行排序。
I guess you could add in the costs.
我想您可以增加费用。
Like associate the costs of B with 4
就像将B的成本与4相关联
and C with 2 within your adjacency list?
和C在您的邻接列表中带有2？
PROFESSOR: So, that's how we would keep track of costs,
教授：因此，这就是我们跟踪成本的方式，
right?
对？
One way.
单程。
AUDIENCE: --for the queue would be A
听众：-因为队列是A
and then the value would be like a [INAUDIBLE] B and its cost,
然后该值将类似于[音频不清晰] B及其费用，
and the [INAUDIBLE] C and its cost.
以及[音频不清晰] C及其成本。
PROFESSOR: So you're saying that what I would have in this list
教授：所以您是说我在这份清单中会得到的
is B with a cost of 4?
是成本为4的B吗？
And C with a cost of 2?
和C的成本为2？
Presumably, the other way around, right?
大概是相反的方式，对吧？
C goes first?
C先走吗？
Like This?
像这样？
And then I take out C, I explore the neighbors so and so forth?
然后我拿出C，然后探索邻居等等？
The moment I did this I already lost the battle.
我这样做的那一刻，我已经输掉了战斗。
Because, see this path A, C, B, length 3?
因为看到此路径A，C，B的长度为3？
If I put both of them in the queue,
如果我把它们都放在队列中，
then the parent pointers are going to look like this.
那么父指针将看起来像这样。
So, I already have a bad path from B to A.
因此，我从B到A的路已经很差。
AUDIENCE: OK, well don't add that node then.
听众：好的，那么不要添加该节点。
PROFESSOR: OK, then how do we do it?
教授：好的，那我们该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: I guess you can talk to each of them
听众：我想你可以和他们每个人谈谈
and see which one's lower and then, only
然后看看哪一个更低
add that one if it's the lowest.
如果是最低的，再加上一个。
So it's more like depth search then--
因此，这更像是深度搜索-
PROFESSOR: Well, you two need to talk together
教授：好，你们两个需要一起聊天
because you're getting to Dijkstra, too.
因为你也要去Dijkstra。
You're both going to rediscover Dijkstra.
你们都将重新发现Dijkstra。
So that's great, but I'm looking for something simple.
太好了，但我正在寻找简单的东西。
This is too complicated.
这太复杂了。
If you're going to do Dijkstra now, then
如果您现在要进行Dijkstra，那么
what are going to do on lecture on Tuesday?
周二的演讲会做什么？
AUDIENCE: More Dijkstra problems?
观众：还有Dijkstra问题吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, I think Shreeny wants to talk about Dijkstra,
教授：好吧，我想Shreeny想谈谈Dijkstra，
so let's not get there.
所以我们不要去那里。
AUDIENCE: How do you do this without doing Dijkstra?
观众：您如何在不执行Dijkstra的情况下做到这一点？
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
That's exactly what I want to know.
这正是我想知道的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
So, let me give you another hint.
所以，让我再给您一个提示。
The first hint was that I want to go through this edge
第一个暗示是我想经历这个边缘
faster than I would go through this edge.
比我经历这个边缘要快。
The other hint is that we're allowed to change the graph.
另一个提示是允许我们更改图表。
AUDIENCE: Is this what we talked about in lecture,
听众：这是我们在演讲中谈到的，
or are we thinking of something else?
还是我们在想其他事情？
PROFESSOR: He might have talked about that
教授：他可能已经谈论过
at the end of lecture.
在讲座结束时。
AUDIENCE: Were you putting the current weight
观众：您是要放当前体重吗
for each node inside the circles?
对于圈子中的每个节点？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
AUDIENCE: You could add it and then
听众：您可以添加它，然后
if you could find a better path to B?
是否可以找到通往B的更好途径？
With rows relative to A, then you
相对于A的行，那么您
could just delete that path?
可以删除该路径吗？
And B to 4?
和B到4？
So at the beginning you add them all, but then--
因此，一开始您将它们全部添加，但是-
PROFESSOR: You're risking to have exponential running time.
教授：您冒着成倍的运行时间的危险。
AUDIENCE: (LAUGHS)
观众：（笑声）
PROFESSOR: Those are all valid optimizations
教授：这些都是有效的优化
under some constraints.
在某些约束下。
Like, this one's good if you don't have too much memory,
就像，如果您没有太多的记忆，这是一件好事，
but the time goes up.
但是时间到了。
I want my graph to have edges with no costs,
我希望我的图表没有成本，
because if I have costs, this is not going to work.
因为如果我有费用，这将无法工作。
BFS is not going to work.
BFS无法正常工作。
We can't tweak it.
我们无法调整它。
If you could tweak it then that would be another Turing Award.
如果您可以调整它，那将是另一个图灵奖。
AUDIENCE: So, create dummy nodes?
听众：那么，创建虚拟节点吗？
PROFESSOR: Create dummy nodes.
教授：创建虚拟节点。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
AUDIENCE:Put a band of node in between A and C?
听众：在A和C之间放置一个节点带？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Why am I doing this?
我为什么要这样做？
So now I have two edges and they have costs.
所以现在我有两个优势，而且它们都有成本。
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
Then you put three nodes in between A and B.
然后将三个节点放在A和B之间。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And now here I have four edges, right?
现在我在这里有四个优势，对吗？
1, 1, 1, 1.
1 1 1
There was a 4 here before and there was a 2 here before.
以前这里有4个，以前这里有2个。
Do you guys see what's happening?
你们看到发生了什么吗？
So, instead of one edge of cost C, I have C edges.
因此，我有C个边，而不是成本C的边。
So, now BFS is going to take C steps to go through that edge.
因此，现在BFS将采取C步骤来穿越该边缘。
And all the edges now have the same cost.
现在所有边缘的成本都相同。
This looks like a problem that BFS can solve.
这似乎是BFS可以解决的问题。
We know it can solve.
我们知道它可以解决。
We proved that it can solve it.
我们证明它可以解决。
Well, CLRS did.
好吧，CLRS做到了。
We take their word for granted, sort of.
我们认为他们的话是理所当然的。
This works right?
这样行吗？
Is everyone happy with it?
每个人都满意吗？
Does it make sense?
是否有意义？
AUDIENCE: So basically, we get through C
听众：基本上，我们通过了C
before you'll get to B on the other path.
在到达另一条路之前，先到达B。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
This is the path of length 3, so this node
这是长度为3的路径，所以这个节点
is going to get in the queue first.
将首先进入队列。
Then this node.
然后是这个节点。
Then these two nodes.
然后这两个节点。
And they're going to get in the queue from C.
他们将从C入队。
Let's see what happened here.
让我们看看这里发生了什么。
This is really important because this
这真的很重要，因为这
is what you're going to be doing in real life.
是您在现实生活中要做的事情。
Chances of having to build a new algorithm?
是否有必要构建新算法？
Kind of slim.
有点苗条。
Why don't you want to do that?
您为什么不想这样做？
Say you take Dijkstra and you tweak it a little bit.
假设您选择了Dijkstra，然后对其进行了一些调整。
If you did that, you have to go through the analysis
如果这样做，则必须进行分析
and prove the running time again,
并再次证明运行时间，
prove the correctness again.
再次证明正确性。
Time-consuming, error-prone, it's really hard.
费时，容易出错，这真的很难。
However, what happened here is that we
但是，这里发生的是
have some problem that we want to solve.
有一些我们要解决的问题。
Say we have the raw input for that problem
说我们有这个问题的原始输入
that we're trying to solve.
我们正在尝试解决的问题。
That is this graph that I draw the board.
这就是我画图的这张图。
And we apply some transform and we
然后我们进行一些变换，
get an input that's suitable for an algorithm
获得适合算法的输入
that we already know.
我们已经知道。
I'm going to take a shortcut here.
我这里要走捷径。
We apply the transform, right?
我们应用转换，对不对？
We took this graph and we built a new graph in.
我们使用了此图，并在其中建立了一个新图。
And this is hopefully easy.
希望这很容易。
Right?
对？
Take an edge and split it up.
占据优势，将其拆分。
Put in fake nodes.
放入假节点。
This is easy.
这很容易。
We know how to code that.
我们知道如何编写代码。
And now we have this algorithm that you already know,
现在我们有了您已经知道的算法
and we're treating it like a black box.
我们将其视为黑匣子。
We know it's correct.
我们知道这是正确的。
We know it's running time.
我们知道这是运行时间。
We're not questioning them.
我们不是在问他们。
We're taking them straight from the textbook.
我们直接从教科书中获取它们。
They have to be right.
他们必须是正确的。
By the way, what's the running time of BFS?
顺便问一下，BFS的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: V plus E?
听众：V加E？
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
Then BFS is going to give us a path, right?
然后BFS会给我们一条路，对吗？
And the path is going to look like this.
路径将看起来像这样。
It's going to be A, fake node, C, D,
它将是A，假节点，C，D，
fake node, E. If you're giving this back to the guy who
假节点E。如果您将其退还给
gave you the problem, they're going to be like,
给你的问题，他们会像
what are these fake nodes?
这些假节点是什么？
I don't know anything about them.
我对他们一无所知。
This doesn't make sense.
这没有道理。
You need to take this raw output and you
您需要获取原始输出，然后
need to transform it again.
需要再次对其进行转换。
Based on what you did this transformation,
根据您所做的转换，
you have to read out the output.
您必须读出输出。
You have to interpret it.
您必须对其进行解释。
So, this is either interpret or readout.
因此，这是解释或读出。
And then you get a nice output that's
然后您会得到一个不错的输出
the output to your original problem.
输出到您原来的问题。
This process here is the most likely way
这是最可能的方法
in which you'll use your 6006 knowledge.
在其中您将使用您的6006知识。
And this is replaced by any algorithm that we taught.
这被我们教过的任何算法所取代。
This is replaced by any real life problem
这被任何现实生活中的问题所取代
that you'll encounter.
你会遇到的。
There's one missing step here.
这里缺少一个步骤。
We know the running time for this.
我们知道运行时间。
Let's find out the running time for the whole thing.
让我们找出整个过程的运行时间。
In order to do that, we have to figure out
为了做到这一点，我们必须弄清楚
given this original graph.
给出这个原始图。
Let's say that now, in the original graph,
假设现在在原始图中
we have V prime vertices, E prime edges, and W
我们有V个素顶点，E个素边缘和W
prime weights.
素重。
We have to convert this into V plus E.
我们必须将其转换为V加E。
We have to see when we make this transform, how many vertices
我们必须看到进行转换时有多少个顶点
do we get?
我们得到吗？
How many edges do we get in terms of the original graph
就原始图形而言，我们可以获得多少条边
so that we can compute the running time?
这样我们才能计算出运行时间？
In the original graph, V prime vertices, E prime edges,
在原始图中，V个素顶点，E个素边缘，
W prime weights.
W质数权重。
In this new graph, how many edges do I have, at most?
在这张新图中，我最多有多少条边？
AUDIENCE: Something times E?
听众：大约是E？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Perfect.
完善。
Each edge has cost at most W. That
每个边的成本最高为W​​。
means we're going to split it up into most W edges.
意味着我们将把它分成大部分W边缘。
How many vertices are we going to have?
我们要有多少个顶点？
AUDIENCE: W prime?
听众：W素数？
PROFESSOR: W prime, E prime.
教授：W素数，E素数。
AUDIENCE: Plus V prime?
听众：加V素数？
PROFESSOR: Plus V prime.
教授：加V素数。
Don't forget about the original ones.
不要忘记原始的。
They're still there.
他们仍然在那里。
So, total running time for BFS on this new graph is?
那么，在这个新图表上BFS的总运行时间是？
AUDIENCE: --E prime.
听众：--E素。
PROFESSOR: Put it the other way around, plus W prime, E prime.
教授：反之，再加上W素数，E素数。
This is the running time that we have.
这是我们的运行时间。
Now, does anyone remember Dijkstra's running time
现在，有谁记得Dijkstra的跑步时间
and Bellam-Ford's running time?
贝拉姆·福特的放映时间？
So what is the running time for Dijkstra?
那么Dijkstra的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: V log V plus E?
听众：V log V加E？
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: V log V?
听众：V log V？
PROFESSOR: Oh, wait.
教授：哦，等等。
I think you're right.
我想你是正确的。
V log V plus--
V log V加-
AUDIENCE: E?
听众：E？
PROFESSOR: I already named this from CRS?
教授：我已经从CRS取这个名字了吗？
Or is this what we got?
还是这是我们得到的？
Entry is a fancy key to give this running time.
进入是赋予此运行时间的理想选择。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You can get this, but you need the really fancy data
教授：可以得到，但是您需要真正的数据
structure for it.
它的结构。
In real life, the running time looks more like E log V.
在现实生活中，运行时间看起来更像E logV。
And how about Bellam-Ford?
贝拉姆·福特怎么样？
So let's take this running time for Dijkstra
因此，让我们把这个运行时间带给Dijkstra
because this is what you're going
因为这就是你要走的
to implement in real life.
在现实生活中实施。
And we can argue about that after next lecture for now.
在下一堂课之后，我们可以就此进行辩论。
Take my word for it.
相信我。
And let's compare it to what we got here.
让我们将其与我们在这里得到的进行比较。
V is smaller than E in most same cases.
在大多数情况下，V小于E。
Let's say that this is actually W prime, E prime.
假设这实际上是W素数，E素数。
If you compare this with this, you'll
如果将此与此进行比较，您将
see that, if W is smaller than log V, well, smaller equal,
可以看到，如果W小于log V，那么等于
then this algorithm is not worse than Dijkstra.
那么这个算法并不比Dijkstra差。
It's on par with Dijkstra.
与Dijkstra相当。
For graphs with small costs, we discovered an algorithm
对于成本小的图，我们发现了一种算法
that solves shortest paths.
解决最短的路径。
You walked into this recitation knowing no algorithm
您走进本课时不知道算法
to solve shortest path.
解决最短路径。
Now we have an algorithm.
现在我们有了一个算法。
Already in a much better position.
已经处于更好的位置。
Right?
对？
And we didn't invent anything new.
而且我们没有发明任何新东西。
We don't have to prove correctness.
我们不必证明正确性。
All we did was one of these transformations.
我们所做的只是这些转换之一。
How's everyone feeling?
大家感觉如何？
Those things makes sense?
那些事情有意义吗？
Everyone happy?
大家开心吗
Let's talk about another problem that also uses this structure.
让我们讨论另一个也使用此结构的问题。
Suppose we have the same graph that we
假设我们有与我们相同的图
had before, or actually, any graph with V vertices, E edges.
之前或实际上具有V顶点，E边的任何图形。
Now we know how to compute shortest paths.
现在我们知道了如何计算最短路径。
So we can assume these as black boxes.
因此，我们可以将这些假设为黑匣子。
We're going to use these as they are.
我们将按原样使用它们。
We have a graph with V vertices and E edges.
我们有一个带有V顶点和E边的图。
Let me copy the costs really quickly.
让我真正迅速地复制费用。
Suppose this is the highway system,
假设这是公路系统，
right, like in Google Maps.
对，就像在Google Maps中一样。
And we have two brothers.
我们有两个兄弟。
They start off from a place and they
他们从一个地方开始，他们
have to end up in another place.
必须在另一个地方结束。
They're going to drive together.
他们将一起开车。
They want this to be sort of fair.
他们希望这是公平的。
Every time they go between two cities
每次他们去两个城市之间
they're going to switch seats so that none of them
他们要换座位，所以他们都不
drives too much.
开车太多。
So say the brothers are Tim and Jim.
可以说兄弟是蒂姆和吉姆。
The names are wrong.
名称错误。
This is actually a problem from last year's quiz.
这实际上是去年测验中的一个问题。
So, by the way, real problem.
因此，顺便说一句，真正的问题。
You can pay attention now.
您现在可以关注。
These are two brothers.
这是两个兄弟。
They're going to alternate.
他们将交替。
Right?
对？
One of them is going to drive across one road,
其中之一将驶过一条路，
then the other one, then the first one, then the second one.
然后是另一个，然后是第一个，然后是第二个。
So on and so forth.
等等等等。
Now, two Tim has a much better sense of direction than Jim.
现在，两个蒂姆比吉姆有更好的方向感。
That's just how things are.
事情就是这样。
And if you ever driven long distances,
如果你开车远距离，
the hardest thing to do is to get from the city
最难的事情是从城市中获得
to the highway.
到高速公路。
Like, if you have to drive from here to New York.
就像，如果您必须从这里开车前往纽约。
Hardest thing to do?
最难做的事？
Get out of Boston and onto the highway.
离开波士顿，驶向高速公路。
Then, at the end, the hardest thing to do?
那么，最后最难的事情是什么？
Get from the highway into where you
从高速公路进入您所在的地方
want to go through New York traffic.
想通过纽约的交通。
Everything else?
还有其他吗
Piece of cake.
小菜一碟。
We want Tim to handle both of these situations.
我们希望蒂姆能够处理这两种情况。
The driving path must start with Tim and must end with Tim.
行驶路径必须以蒂姆开始，并且必须以蒂姆结束。
Otherwise, God knows, they're going to crash.
否则，上帝知道，它们将会崩溃。
First off let's convert this into graph terms.
首先，让我们将其转换为图形项。
And then let's solve it.
然后解决它。
AUDIENCE: You might convert what's already in the graph.
听众：您可能会转换图中已经存在的内容。
PROFESSOR: I have this constraint
教授：我有这个限制
that they're going to switch seats and that Tim has to start
他们要换座位，而蒂姆必须开始
and Tim has to end.
蒂姆必须结束。
How do I phrase this in mathy terms?
我该如何用数学术语表述？
In graph terms?
用图来表示？
AUDIENCE: We're starting it where and ending where?
听众：我们在哪里开始，在哪里结束？
PROFESSOR: We're given where in the graph.
教授：我们在图中的位置。
We're starting at S, ending at T. Some points in the graph.
我们从S开始，在T结束。图中的某些点。
AUDIENCE: And people have to drive with it an entire edge?
听众：人们必须全力以赴吗？
PROFESSOR: Ya.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So basically, Jim has to-- whoever
听众：所以基本上，吉姆必须-
the good driver has to-- to drive on the edge that's
优秀的驾驶员必须-在
adjacent to E and S.
与E和S相邻。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: You physically need, like an odd number of edges.
听众：您实际上需要像奇数个边缘。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So I want the shortest path with an odd number of edges.
所以我想要一条具有奇数个边的最短路径。
Why odd number of edges?
为什么边数奇数？
If we look at the edges, Tim's going to take the first one.
如果我们看看边缘，蒂姆将采取第一个。
Then Jim, then Tim, then Jim, then Tim, then Jim.
然后是Jim，然后是Tim，然后是Jim，然后是Tim，然后是Jim。
No matter how many I have here, it has to end with Tim.
无论我在这里有多少人，都必须以蒂姆结束。
So, I'm going to have an odd number of letters here,
所以，我这里的字母奇数，
therefore, odd number of edges.
因此，边缘数为奇数。
Right?
对？
So I want the shortest path that has an odd number of edges.
所以我想要一条具有奇数个边的最短路径。
And as the hint we're going to use that trick over there.
作为提示，我们将在那儿使用该技巧。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: But, the shortest path isn't necessarily
听众：但是，最短的路径并不一定
like the fairest, right?
像最美丽的吧？
Like, in terms of distributing driving?
喜欢，在分配驾驶方面？
PROFESSOR: One of them is going to drive one more road,
教授：其中一个人要再开一条路，
such is life.
这就是生活。
Sorry, one more edge segment.
抱歉，还有一个边缘部分。
Tim's going to drive three times,
蒂姆要开车三遍，
Jim is going to drive two times.
吉姆要开车两次。
AUDIENCE: Right, but like, in terms of the weights?
听众：对，但是就重量而言？
PROFESSOR: Oh, yeah.
教授：哦，是的。
We don't care about that.
我们不在乎。
Jim doesn't know where he's going anyways.
吉姆不知道他要去哪里。
AUDIENCE: Just a minimum, we have to have like three paths,
听众：至少，我们必须走三条路，
right?
对？
We don't just want Tim to get out to the highway
我们不只是希望蒂姆走上高速公路
and be like, oh look our journey's not that far--
就像，哦，看来我们的旅程不远了-
PROFESSOR: So I went to the path with the smallest cost.
教授：所以我去了成本最低的道路。
So, smallest total weight.
因此，总重量最小。
AUDIENCE: In theory it could be length, too.
听众：从理论上讲，它也可以是长度。
Right?
对？
PROFESSOR: Well, if it's length, too,
教授：好吧，如果也是，
then it's not going to be good because they're going to crash.
那就不好了，因为它们会崩溃。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
They have to switch every time.
他们每次都必须切换。
PROFESSOR: Tim can't drive for two consecutive edges.
教授：蒂姆不能连续两个边缘开车。
AUDIENCE: You could use breadth-first search
听众：您可以使用广度优先搜索
and, once you get to the end point,
而且，一旦到达终点，
or made all paths that are [INAUDIBLE] and then,
或将所有路径设为[音频不清晰]，然后，
of those paths, go through to see
在这些路径中，经历看看
which one's the lowest cost?
哪个费用最低？
PROFESSOR: You're thinking enumerate
教授：您正在考虑列举
all paths of even length?
所有长度均等的路径？
Just to make sure I got it.
只是为了确保我明白了。
So this is cool because it let's me
所以这很酷，因为它让我
show something else that's cool.
展示其他很酷的东西。
So, enumerate all paths of even length.
因此，请列举所有长度均匀的路径。
Something else I heard, enumerate
我还听到了其他一些东西
all the shortest paths.
所有最短的路径。
For both of these, let's look at this graph.
对于这两种情况，让我们看一下这张图。
S, T, all the paths have length 1.
S，T，所有路径的长度为1。
How many ways are there to get from S to T?
从S到T有多少种方法？
AUDIENCE: Two to three.
听众：二到三。
PROFESSOR: Two to three.
教授：两到三个。
Two ways to go across this diamond.
穿越这颗钻石的两种方法。
Two ways to go across this one.
有两种方法可以解决这一问题。
Right?
对？
2 times 2 times 2?
2 2 2
8.
8。
If I add another diamond, how many paths?
如果我添加另一个菱形，有多少条路径？
One more?
多一个？
So the number of even paths, or the number of shortest paths,
因此，偶数路径数或最短路径数
the number of whatever paths I can think about is, order of?
我能想到的任何路径的数量是多少？
Come on, guys.
拜托了伙计们。
Math.
数学。
Rrrr!
rr！
Go!
走！
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: 2 to a number of diamonds?
观众：2颗钻石？
PROFESSOR: Which is?
教授：那是什么？
Roughly to the vertices.
大致到顶点。
Exponential in the number of vertices.
顶点数的指数。
Not very good, not very good.
不是很好，不是很好。
We can't do this.
我们做不到
So, it's better that we talked about it here,
因此，最好在这里讨论它，
then that you try to do it on the quiz
然后您尝试在测验中做到这一点
and you have to discover this on your own, right?
而且您必须自己发现它，对吧？
Good comment.
好评论。
AUDIENCE: Didn't understand what you meant by that lecture.
听众：听不懂那堂课的意思。
Now it makes sense.
现在有道理了。
PROFESSOR: That's completely different.
教授：那是完全不同的。
AUDIENCE: That wasn't the thing he was talking about?
听众：那不是他在说的吗？
PROFESSOR: That's different.
教授：不一样。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: That's where relaxation can go wrong.
教授：那是放松的地方。
So if you show that if you relax the edges in a random order,
因此，如果您证明以随机顺序放松边缘，
you can have an exponential number of steps.
您可以有指数级的步骤。
This shows that there are an exponential number of paths
这表明路径的数量是指数的
for any graph, no matter how good your algorithm is.
对于任何图形，无论您的算法有多好。
So we're not going to be able to enumerate them.
因此，我们将无法枚举它们。
Let's try something else.
让我们尝试其他事情。
AUDIENCE: You have another suggestion?
听众：您还有其他建议吗？
Just look at all the--
只要看看所有-
PROFESSOR: So, you're doing this.
教授：所以，您正在这样做。
You're looking here.
你在这儿
Everyone's looking here.
大家都在看
How about this?
这个怎么样？
AUDIENCE: We should do that?
听众：我们应该这样做吗？
PROFESSOR: Ther's that, right?
教授：就是这样吗？
There's a transform.
有一个转变。
You need to transform your graph in some way,
您需要以某种方式变换图形，
then run the algorithm.
然后运行算法。
And then reading off the outputs should be easy.
然后读取输出应该很容易。
I claim that the hard step is the transform step, not
我声称困难的步骤是转换步骤，而不是
the read off step.
读取步骤。
Let me give you one more piece of intuition.
让我再给你一个直觉。
We're going to keep track of states, somehow.
我们将以某种方式跟踪状态。
Remember Rubik's cube?
还记得魔方的魔方吗？
We had one vertex for each state.
每个状态都有一个顶点。
A state representing the configuration of the cube.
表示多维数据集配置的状态。
Here, suppose I'm looking at the path from S
在这里，假设我正在寻找从S出发的路径
to D. The problem that I have with this
给D。我有这个问题
is that, if I have an algorithm that tells me the shortest
是的，如果我有一个算法可以告诉我最短的算法
path from S to D is something, I don't know if it's even
从S到D的路径是东西，我什至不知道
or if it's odd.
还是很奇怪
It's not keeping track of that.
它没有跟踪。
It's missing some state.
它缺少某些状态。
The state that it's missing is whether the path
缺少的状态是路径是否
that I used to get here is even or odd length.
我以前来这里的长度是偶数还是奇数。
I should do something to the graph
我应该对图做点事
to keep track of this state.
跟踪此状态。
AUDIENCE: Can you BFS it once?
听众：可以一次BFS吗？
To plan-- You BFS once.
计划-您一次BFS。
Then you that B and C are all like 108,
那么你B和C都像108
and then you know that E and D are 208?
然后你知道E和D是208？
PROFESSOR: B 208 if I take this path.
教授：如果我走这条路，请到B 208。
It might be 108, might be 208.
可能是108，可能是208。
But, this is good.
但是，这很好。
This is what you'll do on a quiz, right?
这就是您要进行的测验，对吧？
You come up with an idea and then
你想出一个主意，然后
you're going to think about it for a bit.
您将考虑一下。
If you get stuck, try to convince yourself
如果遇到困难，请尝试说服自己
that it's wrong.
这是错误的。
If things get too hard, discard and look somewhere else.
如果事情变得太难了，则丢弃并找其他地方。
This is thought process, right?
这是思考过程，对吗？
You think of something, backtrack, backtrack,
您想到的是回溯，回溯，
backtrack, and eventually you get to the right solution.
回溯，最终找到正确的解决方案。
Let's go over the solution for this one,
让我们来看一下这个解决方案，
and then I'll give you a hard one that is sort of like this.
然后我会给你一个像这样的硬汉。
Then I'll want the solution from you for that one.
然后，我希望从您那里获得解决方案。
I'm going to draw this graph in a bigger version,
我将以更大的版本绘制此图，
so I'll have to erase this.
所以我必须删除它。
So this is a cool concept.
因此，这是一个很酷的概念。
You will be able to do a lot of things with it.
您将可以用它做很多事情。
AUDIENCE: Is this one solvable by Dijkstra?
听众：Dijkstra可以解决这个问题吗？
PROFESSOR: Ya.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Just curious.
听众：很好奇。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, we'll run Dijkstra on it
教授：是的，我们将在其上运行Dijkstra
after we transform it.
改造之后
These are big nodes!
这些是大节点！
Why am I doing it this way?
我为什么要这样呢？
AUDIENCE: (LAUGHS) Is that like, Seattle, Portland, San
观众：（笑声）就像西雅图，波特兰，圣
Francisco?
弗朗西斯科？
PROFESSOR: It's because I'm going to need room for copies.
教授：这是因为我需要复印的空间。
I'm going to make a copy of each node to keep track of state.
我将制作每个节点的副本以跟踪状态。
AUDIENCE: Gosh.
听众：天哪。
PROFESSOR: So, instead of one node
教授：所以，而不是一个节点
I'll have two nodes for each node.
每个节点有两个节点。
And I have two nodes because this
我有两个节点，因为
is what lets me keep track of state, odd path or even path.
是什么让我跟踪状态，奇数路径甚至偶数路径。
Let me erase the edges because that's not
让我抹掉边缘，因为那不是
how it's going to work, actually.
实际上如何运作。
Instead of having a node A, I'm going to have a node A even.
除了拥有节点A，我还要拥有一个节点A。
And I'm going to have a copy, A odd.
我要去复印，奇怪。
E even, I'm going to have to copy, V odd.
E偶，我将不得不复制，V奇。
C even, copies to C odd.
C偶数，复制到C奇数。
D even, make a copy to D odd.
D偶数，将副本复制到D奇数。
Wait, this is E, sorry.
等等，这是E，对不起。
Sorry, my bad.
对不起这是我的错。
[QUIET TALKING]
[安静交谈]
Suppose I got to A using an even length path.
假设我使用平均长度路径到达A。
If I take the edge from A to B, I
如果我从A到B占据优势，我
will get to B using an even length path, or an odd length
将使用偶数长度或奇数长度的路径到达B
path?
路径？
AUDIENCE: Odd.
听众：奇怪。
PROFESSOR: So, if I get to A using an even length path, then
教授：所以，如果我使用平均长度的路径到达A，
from there I'll get to B using an odd length path.
从那里，我将使用奇长路径到达B。
Sorry, four.
对不起，四个。
Using this exact road.
使用这条确切的路。
AUDIENCE: A really messed-up graph.
听众：一个非常混乱的图表。
PROFESSOR: That's a nice way to name it.
教授：这是一个好名字。
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
[女子笑声]
I've heard worse.
我听得更糟。
If I get to A using an odd number of edges,
如果我用奇数个边到A，
how many edges will I have and I get to B?
我将拥有多少条边，然后到达B？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So this edge became these edges here.
教授：所以这条边变成了这些边。
Now let's do the edge between B and E.
现在让我们来做B和E之间的优势。
I get to be using an even number of edges.
我开始使用偶数个边缘。
I take B. Do I get to the even or to the odd?
我选B。我会达到偶数还是奇数？
AUDIENCE: Odd.
听众：奇怪。
PROFESSOR: I get to B using an odd path.
教授：我是通过一条奇怪的路到达B的。
What are the lengths of these paths?
这些路径的长度是多少？
AUDIENCE: 5.
听众：5。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
God, this is starting to look ugly, you're right.
天哪，这看起来很难看，你是对的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Let's do A, C and stop there.
让我们做A，C，然后停在那里。
A even is connected to?
一个偶数连接到？
AUDIENCE: Odd.
听众：奇怪。
PROFESSOR: C odd, by a path the length.
教授：C奇数，按路径的长度。
And A odd is connected to C even by a path of length.
奇数通过一条长度路径连接到C。
Is this starting to make sense?
这开始有意义吗？
So all the edges are going to look like this.
因此，所有边缘都将看起来像这样。
AUDIENCE: So are those like two independent graphs?
听众：那么那些像两个独立的图吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, I have edges connecting them.
教授：好吧，我在连接它们时有优势。
But, I like your question.
但是，我喜欢你的问题。
The reason this is ugly is because I'm
这个丑陋的原因是因为我
looking at a 2D projection of a 3D graph.
看着3D图形的2D投影。
If I had a holographic display, which would be a lot nicer,
如果我有全息显示器，那就更好了，
then I would do something along these lines.
然后我会按照这些方针做点事。
Two pieces of paper.
两张纸。
I would draw the original graph, and call it the even graph.
我会绘制原始图形，并将其称为偶数图形。
Put it here.
放在这里。
I would draw the graph again, call it the odd graph,
我会再次绘制该图，称为奇数图，
and put it here.
放在这里
So this is my 2D graph.
这是我的2D图形。
This is my map, the original map.
这是我的地图，原始地图。
And this is state.
这是状态。
The third dimension is state.
第三维是状态。
When I'm at a node, and I used an even number of edges
当我在节点上时，我使用了偶数个边
to get here, I'm going to go take one edge
到这里，我要走一个优势
and go to another node using an odd number of edges.
然后使用奇数个边缘转到另一个节点。
So all the edges are going to go from here
所以所有的边缘都会从这里消失
to here, and from here to here.
到这里，从这里到这里。
Does it makes more sense now?
现在更有意义了吗？
So the reason that looks ugly is because you're
所以看起来丑陋的原因是因为你
seeing the graph like this.
看到这样的图。
If you could see like this, and maybe play with it
如果您可以看到这样的画面，也许可以玩
a little bit, it would make more sense.
一点，这将更有意义。
It wouldn't look as ugly.
看起来并不难看。
There are two graphs, the even graph and the odd graph.
有两个图，偶数图和奇数图。
And the edges between them represent you doing something.
它们之间的边缘代表您正在做某事。
When you take the highway, you transition from an even state
上高速公路时，您会从平坦状态过渡
to an odd state, and from an odd state to an even state.
从奇数状态到偶数状态。
So that's why the edges are the way they are.
这就是为什么边缘是它们的样子。
Now let me see if you guys get it.
现在让我看看你们是否明白。
What node do I start from?
我从哪个节点开始？
What node do I want to end up in?
我想在哪个节点结束？
AUDIENCE: A, and you're ending up at B?
听众：A，而您最终将到达B？
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, there's two--
听众：哦，有两个
PROFESSOR: I heard three answers.
教授：我听到了三个答案。
One of them is correct.
其中之一是正确的。
Do you want to vote or do you guys want to figure it out?
您要投票还是要弄清楚？
Talk it out?
说出来吗
Fight?
斗争？
AUDIENCE: A even, E odd.
听众：偶数，奇数。
PROFESSOR: We start from A even and we end up at E odd.
教授：我们从A偶数开始，到E奇数结束。
Why do I started at A even?
为什么我甚至从A开始？
AUDIENCE: We've seen exactly zero cities
观众：我们已经看到了零个城市
when we started out.
当我们开始的时候。
PROFESSOR: Yep, so the original path
教授：是的，所以原来的路径
has length the 0, which happens to be even.
长度为0，恰好是偶数。
And we want to end up with an odd length path.
我们希望最终得到一条奇数长度的路径。
So if we go from here to here-- see how
所以，如果我们从这里到这里-看看如何
because we have two nodes out of each original node,
因为我们在每个原始节点中都有两个节点，
the path is going to alternate between even and odd.
路径将在偶数和奇数之间交替。
And is going to keep track of the state
并将跟踪状态
that they didn't have before, and it's
他们以前没有的
going to just do the right thing.
去做正确的事。
It's magic!
这是魔法！
It works!
有用！
Let's see what is the running this new algorithm.
让我们看看运行这种新算法的情况。
Say my original graph had V and E.
假设我的原始图形有V和E。
How many new vertices do I have?
我有几个新顶点？
AUDIENCE: Two kinds.
听众：两种。
PROFESSOR: How many edges?
教授：几条边？
AUDIENCE: Twice?
听众：两次？
PROFESSOR: Each edge is copied exactly twice.
教授：每个边精确地复制了两次。
Which algorithm am I going to use?
我要使用哪种算法？
All my weights are positive because they're
我所有的重量都是正的，因为它们
the time it takes to drive somewhere,
开车去某个地方的时间
the distance or something.
距离之类的。
So which algorithm do I use?
那么我该使用哪种算法？
AUDIENCE: Breadth-first search?
听众：广度优先搜索？
PROFESSOR: We can't use breadth-first search
教授：我们无法使用广度优先搜索
because you have weight.
因为你有体重。
So breadth-first search is not going to find the right answer.
因此，广度优先搜索不会找到正确的答案。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Oh, you want to use this thing.
教授：哦，你想用这个东西。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Well, so we don't have
教授：好吧，所以我们没有
to worry about that because now we put the shortest path
担心这一点，因为现在我们走了最短的道路
algorithm in the black box and we have them.
黑盒中的算法，我们有它们。
AUDIENCE: Oh, so we can use them now.
听众：哦，所以我们现在就可以使用它们。
PROFESSOR: We use these black boxes.
教授：我们使用这些黑匣子。
But what we need to know is when to use this black box
但是我们需要知道的是何时使用这个黑匣子
and when is this black box.
这个黑匣子是什么时候
Which boxes faster, by the way?
顺便说一下，哪个盒子更快？
Please, please give me the right answer.
请，请给我正确的答案。
AUDIENCE: Dijkstra?
听众：Dijkstra？
PROFESSOR: All right!
教授：好的！
Dijkstra is faster.
Dijkstra更快。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
So whenever we can use Dijkstra we will use Dijkstra.
因此，只要我们可以使用Dijkstra，就将使用Dijkstra。
When can't we use Dijkstra?
我们什么时候不能使用Dijkstra？
AUDIENCE: When it's negative, [INAUDIBLE].
听众：否定时，[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Negative--
教授：负面
AUDIENCE: Weights.
听众：重量。
PROFESSOR: Negative weights.
教授：负权数。
If I have weights greater or equal to 0,
如果我的权重大于或等于0，
I'm happy I can use Dijkstra.
我很高兴可以使用Dijkstra。
If I have weights that are smaller than 0, well, whatever.
如果我的权重小于0，那么无论如何。
It's going to be slower, but I can still solve it.
速度会变慢，但我仍然可以解决。
AUDIENCE: It's like arbitrary negative weights.
听众：这就像任意负重。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Arbitrary negative weights.
任意负权重。
So all the edges here are positive, so I'm going to use--
所以这里的所有边缘都是积极的，所以我将使用-
AUDIENCE: Dijkstra.
听众：Dijkstra。
PROFESSOR: Dijkstra!
教授：Dijkstra！
Very good.
很好。
So the running time will be, order of--
因此，运行时间约为-
AUDIENCE: V log V?
听众：V log V？
PROFESSOR: V log V plus E. If you're a theory person,
教授：V log V加E。如果您是理论人士，
if you're in real life it's E log V.
如果您在现实生活中，则为E logV。
This is exactly the running time for the original graph.
这正是原始图形的运行时间。
The transformation only increased the graph size
转换只会增加图形大小
by a constant factor.
不变的因素。
So, same running time.
因此，相同的运行时间。
Pretty good, right?
还不错吧？
OK, let's do one more problem.
好，让我们再做一个问题。
Let's do the hard problem now.
让我们现在解决这个难题。
Are you guys getting ready for the hard problem?
你们准备好迎接这个难题了吗？
AUDIENCE: If we hadn't seen this probably
听众：如果我们可能没有看到这个
wouldn't have thought of it.
不会想到的。
I wouldn't even think about this.
我什至不会考虑这一点。
PROFESSOR: Well, that's why we taught you this.
教授：好的，这就是我们教你这个原因的原因。
So I wanted to do two things.
所以我想做两件事。
I wanted to show you that trick, which is a cool trick,
我想向您展示这个技巧，这很酷，
keep track of state by multiplying
通过相乘来跟踪状态
the vertices that you have.
您拥有的顶点。
And I wanted to go through some wrong solutions
我想通过一些错误的解决方案
and figure out why they're wrong so you
弄清楚为什么他们错了，所以你
can develop an intuition.
可以发展直觉。
Because, when you're going to get a new problem,
因为，当您遇到新问题时，
you're going to think of something.
你会想一些事情。
Unless you're really good, unless you
除非你真的很好，除非你
are destined to win a Turing Award of some sort,
注定要获得图灵奖，
the first solution will probably be wrong.
第一个解决方案可能是错误的。
Even if you're destined to win a Turing Award,
即使您注定要获得图灵奖，
the first thing that comes to mind will probably be wrong.
首先想到的可能是错误的。
I'm willing to bet Dijkstra didn't think of Dijkstra
我愿意打赌Dijkstra没想到Dijkstra
off the top of his head when he heard about the problem.
听说这个问题时，他的头顶掉了。
What you want to do is get an intuition.
您想要做的就是获得直觉。
So you think of a solution and it starts getting complicated,
所以您想到一个解决方案，它开始变得复杂，
or things start looking wrong, you
或事情开始看起来不对，你
want to back out and think of something else.
想退出并想其他事情。
The more things we can consider, higher chances that you're
我们可以考虑的事情越多，您获得的机会就越高
going to stumble upon the correct solution.
会偶然发现正确的解决方案。
So that's why we are building an intuition for bad solutions.
因此，这就是我们为不良解决方案建立直觉的原因。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I'm not just saying, hey, give me a solution
我不只是说，嘿，给我一个解决方案
and now I'll tell you it's wrong.
现在我告诉你这是错误的。
It's not just to embarrass you or something.
这不只是让您感到尴尬。
There's that intuition building step.
有直觉的建立步骤。
That's really important.
那真的很重要。
There's this network that we keep talking about.
我们一直在谈论这个网络。
There's this highway network, except this time
除了这次有公路网
it's a bit more complicated.
这有点复杂。
So for each edge I have two things.
所以对于每个边缘我都有两件事。
I have a fuel cost, which is constant.
我的油费是固定的。
A fuel cost is a function of the length of the road.
燃油成本是道路长度的函数。
But now, I have these realistic highways where I have traffic.
但是现在，我在这些现实的高速公路上有交通。
If you try to go from Boston to New York, 2 AM?
如果您尝试从波士顿凌晨2点去纽约？
Three hours.
三个小时。
Rush hour?
高峰时间？
Six hours.
六个小时。
So we have to keep track of this in some way.
因此，我们必须以某种方式对此进行跟踪。
Well we're going to split up the day into minutes.
好吧，我们将把时间分成几分钟。
Say you have 10 minutes in a day.
假设您每天有10分钟。
Can anyone tell me what M is, really quickly?
谁能很快告诉我M是什么？
Not a number, a formula, something.
不是数字，公式或其他东西。
AUDIENCE: What's 3,600 times 24?
观众：3,600乘24是多少？
And that's seconds.
那是几秒钟。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So this is how many minutes in a day.
因此，这是一天中的分钟数。
This is how many minutes we have in a day, right?
这是我们一天有几分钟的时间，对吗？
For each edge, we're going to have a function that's
对于每个边缘，我们将具有一个
the time cost of the edge.
边缘的时间成本。
So it's the time cost of this edge, and it's going to say,
所以这是此优势的时间成本，并且会说，
if I start at a certain time, it's
如果我在某个时间开始，那就是
going to take this many minutes to go across the edge.
要花这么多分钟才能穿越边缘。
For each highway I know how much time
我知道每条高速公路要花费多少时间
it's going to take to go across it, given when I start.
当我开始的时候，将会经历它。
And I know much fuel I'm going to consume.
而且我知道我要消耗很多燃料。
By the way, edges are directed now, just
顺便说一句，现在就将边缘指向
to make our life easy.
使我们的生活变得轻松。
This graph is going to be like this.
该图将是这样的。
Let's see if I can get this right.
让我们看看我能不能正确解决这个问题。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So the real reason I'm
教授：所以我真正的原因是
having this is the time to go across the highway
这是时候过高速公路了
might be different, depending which way you go.
可能会有所不同，具体取决于您走的路。
AUDIENCE:Oh--
观众：哦-
PROFESSOR: Getting into Boston in the morning
教授：早上去波士顿
versus getting into Boston in the evening.
而不是晚上去波士顿。
Which one's easier?
哪个更容易？
Sorry, versus getting out of Boston in the morning.
对不起，早上要离开波士顿。
Intuitively, I'd say it's probably harder
凭直觉，我会说这可能更难
to get in in the morning because people are going to work.
早上起床，因为人们要去上班。
And it's easier to get out.
而且更容易下车。
But ya, I don't know either.
但是，我也不知道。
AUDIENCE: The 95 one's a hurdle.
听众：95人是一个障碍。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR:We have an answer.
教授：我们有一个答案。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Our edges are going to be oriented.
我们的优势将定位。
I want to find an itinerary that satisfies two constraints.
我想找到一个满足两个约束的行程。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Ya, that's not good, right?
教授：是的，那不好，对吗？
New York and New York.
纽约和纽约。
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
[女子笑声]
So I want to see how fast I can get to my destination.
所以我想看看我能多快到达目的地。
That's my top priority.
这是我的首要任务。
If I get to New York at 5:00 PM, I want to get there at 5:00 PM.
如果我在下午5:00到达纽约，我想在下午5:00到达那里。
I don't want to get there at 5:01, for example.
例如，我不想在5:01到达那里。
But if I have three ways to get there at 5:00 PM,
但是，如果我有3种方法在下午5:00到达那里，
I want to choose the way that's the most eco-friendly.
我想选择最环保的方式。
So, the least amount of fuel.
因此，最少的燃料。
So out of all possible ways, the fastest way?
那么，从所有可能的方法中，最快的方法是什么？
Out of all possible fastest ways,
在所有可能的最快方法中，
the way that consumes the least fuel?
消耗最少燃料的方式？
Go.
走。
You have two minutes.
你有两分钟
Maybe five.
也许五个。
AUDIENCE: And we have the same costs for the--
观众：而且我们为-
PROFESSOR: Each edge always has the same fuel cost.
教授：每个边总是有相同的燃料成本。
But, depending on when you start, going across it
但是，视您开始的时间而定
is going to take a different time, too.
也将花费不同的时间。
AUDIENCE: And we don't know what those times are?
听众：我们不知道那时候是什么时候？
PROFESSOR: They're going to be different for each edge.
教授：每个方面都会有所不同。
AUDIENCE: One guess, take Dijkstra.
听众：一个猜想，以迪克斯特拉为例。
Find the shortest path length and we
找到最短的路径长度，我们
look for all path lengths that are that length.
查找该长度的所有路径长度。
I don't know.
我不知道。
PROFESSOR: So we have the issue that-- I might still have it.
教授：所以我们有一个问题-我可能仍然有。
Oh no, never mind.
哦，不，没关系。
Sorry, I erased it so it's not on your mind anymore.
抱歉，我删除了它，因此您不再在意它了。
We have those diamonds that show you
我们有那些钻石向您展示
that there might be an exponential number of paths
可能存在指数级的路径
with the same length, or the same distance.
具有相同的长度或相同的距离。
AUDIENCE: And it doesn't help that we
观众：而且这对我们没有帮助
know we should cut off the--
知道我们应该切断-
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
So we need to do the process that I just erased.
因此，我们需要执行刚刚删除的过程。
Transform the graph in.
转换图形。
The thing is, now you're missing state, right?
问题是，现在您缺少状态，对吗？
This misses state.
这错过了状态。
This tells you how many edges you
告诉你你有多少条边
have to get from source to destination.
必须从源头到目的地。
But we're not keeping track of some state that these vital.
但是我们没有跟踪这些至关重要的状态。
Transform the graph to keep track of state,
变换图形以跟踪状态，
run, say Dijkstra, and then interpret the output.
运行，例如Dijkstra，然后解释输出。
What state do we need?
我们需要什么状态？
Let's think of that.
让我们考虑一下。
AUDIENCE: Fuel cost, I think.
听众：我想是燃料成本。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: The two costs is the same for each edge.
听众：每条边的两个成本相同。
It's just the time is different.
只是时间不同了。
To be in traffic.
待在交通中。
AUDIENCE: But once we have found the fastest spot
观众：但是一旦我们找到了最快的位置
that we wanted to see cut into our fuel cost range
我们希望看到削减了我们的燃料成本范围
and which one do we want to take.
以及我们要选哪一个。
Thinking about the priority, our priority is time.
考虑优先事项，我们的优先事项是时间。
So we want to save fuels as a state, to check it?
因此，我们想节省燃料以进行检查吗？
PROFESSOR: The problem is I don't even
教授：问题是我什至没有
know if fuel costs are integers.
知道燃料成本是否是整数。
I can't keep fuel as a state.
我不能保持精力充沛。
How many copies would I have?
我要多少份？
For each vertex how many copies would
每个顶点有多少个副本
I have if fuel is a state?
我有没有加油的状态？
Who knows?
谁知道？
So let's try something else.
因此，让我们尝试其他事情。
But, you're on the right track.
但是，您的方向正确。
Let's take a variable and make it state.
让我们接受一个变量并将其设为状态。
AUDIENCE: So for every vertex can you keep
听众：所以您可以保留每个顶点
track of what's the shortest time it took to get there?
到那里最短的时间是什么？
PROFESSOR: What's the shortest time it took to get there?
教授：到那里最短的时间是什么？
How would you keep track of that?
您将如何跟踪？
Would you make that state, or how
你会说那种状态吗？
would you keep track of that?
您会跟踪吗？
I'm not disagreeing.
我不同意。
I'm trying to understand your--
我正试图了解您-
AUDIENCE: So for example, let's say if you have B, right?
观众：例如，假设您有B，对吧？
Let's say it takes like one hour to go from A to B.
假设从A到B大约需要一个小时。
PROFESSOR: It depends when you start, by the way.
教授：顺便说一下，这取决于您何时开始。
How much time it takes depends on when you start.
需要多少时间取决于您何时开始。
If you start at 8:00 AM, it might be an hour.
如果您从8:00 AM开始，则可能需要一个小时。
If you start at 9:00 AM it might be two hours.
如果您从9:00 AM开始，则可能需要两个小时。
AUDIENCE: Do you need to have a finite number of states?
听众：您是否需要有限数量的州？
PROFESSOR: It's nice if it's not infinite,
教授：如果不是无限的，那就太好了，
but it doesn't have to be constant, like we had before.
但这并不需要像我们以前那样恒定。
It can be more than constant, for sure.
当然，它可以不仅仅是常数。
So what are you thinking?
那你在想什么
AUDIENCE: I want to use time as a state.
听众：我想以时间为状态。
PROFESSOR: I like that idea.
教授：我喜欢这个主意。
Let's try to do it.
让我们尝试去做。
We're going to use time as a state.
我们将使用时间作为状态。
How many vertices am I going to have for each vertex?
每个顶点要有多少个顶点？
So for each original vertex, how many vertices
因此，对于每个原始顶点，有多少个顶点
am I going to have in my new graph?
我要在新图表中显示吗？
AUDIENCE: Three or four [INAUDIBLE].
听众：三到四个[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: The sum of all times?
听众：所有时间的总和？
PROFESSOR: So if I say, hey, I'm at this vertex at this time,
教授：所以，如果我说，嘿，我目前处于这个顶点，
then I'm going to have M vertices
那我要有M个顶点
for each original vertex, right?
对于每个原始顶点，对不对？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: I promise that the resolution of time is minutes.
教授：我保证时间的分钟数是分钟。
I promise that this thing gives you
我保证这东西会给你
an integer number of minutes.
分钟的整数。
AUDIENCE: Can it be put into days, though?
听众：但是可以放几天吗？
PROFESSOR: Suppose we can get from source to destination
教授：假设我们可以从源头到达目的地
in one day.
一天内。
So let's see how it builds this graph first,
因此，让我们先看看它如何构建该图，
and then we can figure out the rest of the things.
然后我们可以找出其余的事情。
So for each node I'm going to make M copies of it.
因此，对于每个节点，我将为其制作M个副本。
Suppose in my original graph I had a node.
假设在我的原始图中有一个节点。
I'm going to have M copies of that node.
我将拥有该节点的M个副本。
And each copy has the original vertex,
每个副本都有原始顶点
and the time when I'm there.
还有我在那里的时间
Right?
对？
There are V of these.
这些有V。
And there are M of these.
有M个。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: It totally makes sense.
听众：完全有道理。
It's a great idea.
好主意。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, you had it!
教授：是的，您拥有了！
Great idea.
好想法。
So far so good.
到现在为止还挺好。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: Now they need to be connected
听众：现在需要连接
to the appropriate next one.
到适当的下一个。
PROFESSOR: Let's hear how we do that.
教授：让我们听听我们是如何做到的。
Suppose we have an edge from U to V.
假设我们有一条从U到V的边。
How are going to connect this?
如何连接呢？
How are we going to transform this?
我们该如何改变呢？
How many edges are going to make from that edge?
该边缘将要形成多少个边缘？
AUDIENCE: Do you have to do it from every start time?
听众：您是否必须从每个开始时间开始？
I guess.
我猜。
So you'd write M edges.
所以你要写M条边。
PROFESSOR: M edges.
教授：M条边。
From U and a start time to V and what?
从U到开始时间到V，又是什么？
AUDIENCE:T plus T C of T.
听众：T加上T的TC。
PROFESSOR: T plus T C of going through that edge.
教授：经历那个边缘的T加TC。
Right?
对？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: T C are going from U to V at the stop.
教授：TC在停靠站从U到V。
Ya, like this.
嗯，像这样。
So you start from a time.
因此，您从一个时间开始。
So the edge points from the time that you start up
所以边缘点从您开始时起
until the time when you'd be able to finish.
直到您能够完成的时间为止。
So, up until the time where you'd be off the highway
因此，直到您离开高速公路为止
and die in the next city.
死在下一个城市
And we need one more type of edges.
我们还需要另一种类型的边缘。
There's one more tiny trick.
还有一个小技巧。
If I'm somewhere in Massachusetts, and I know that
如果我在马萨诸塞州的某个地方，我知道
it's really bad now.
现在真的很糟糕。
I prefer to wait out for a few minutes, go to a bar,
我宁愿等几分钟，去酒吧，
and then come and drive-- OK not to a bar-- go to a food place,
然后开车去-好吧，不要去酒吧-去吃饭的地方，
then drive later.
然后再开车。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: --vertical edges that--
听众：-垂直边缘-
PROFESSOR: --represent waiting.
教授：-代表等待。
AUDIENCE: You have to add one minute between them.
听众：您必须在两者之间增加一分钟。
PROFESSOR: How do I do that?
教授：我该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: From U to U with a cost of 1.
观众：从U到U，费用为1。
PROFESSOR: So from U to U at 20 plus 1.
教授：所以从U到U在20加1。
I like this better.
我比较喜欢这个。
What's the fuel cost of this?
燃料成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
PROFESSOR: So here this edge had fuel cost at C,
教授：所以这里的优势是燃料成本为C，
Then the new edge is going have fuel
然后新的优势将不断发展
cost for the ones on the top.
顶部的成本。
AUDIENCE: Is it proportional to minutes?
听众：与分钟成正比吗？
Speed?
速度？
PROFESSOR: It's the same.
教授：一样。
F C stays the same, no matter when we go through the highway
无论我们何时通过高速公路，FC都保持不变
if C is a function of the distance of the road.
如果C是道路距离的函数。
This edge becomes M edges with the same cost.
该边变为M边，且成本相同。
And then I have to have vertical waiting edges.
然后我必须有垂直的等待边缘。
If we had the holographic display
如果我们有全息显示器
that I talked about earlier you'd have M sheets of paper
我刚才说过的你会有M张纸
this time.
这次。
You start at time 0 at your source
您从源头的时间0开始
and then your edges go represent the moves that you can make.
然后您的边缘代表您可以进行的动作。
So, you could start in Boston at 8:00 AM.
因此，您可以从8:00 AM在波士顿开始。
And you could take I-90 and end up
然后您可以乘坐I-90到达终点
in-- I don't know Massachusetts city names-- Albuquerque
在-我不知道马萨诸塞州的城市名称-阿尔伯克基
at 9:00 AM?
在9:00 AM？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: Amherst.
听众：阿默斯特。
PROFESSOR: Amherst, OK.
教授：阿默斯特，好的。
So you started in Boston 8:00 AM,
所以您从8:00 AM在波士顿开始，
you end up at Amherst at 9, 10:00 AM.
您将在上午9点10:00在阿默斯特（Amherst）结束。
Right?
对？
So this is one edge.
所以这是一个优势。
The edges represent the moves that you
边缘代表您的举动
could make in this graph.
可以在这张图中。
Does this makes?
这会吗？
AUDIENCE: I don't understand the two last lines there.
听众：我不明白那里的最后两行。
I don't really get what we were doing there [INAUDIBLE].
我真的不明白我们在那儿所做的[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Let's see what we're trying to do here.
教授：让我们看看我们要在这里做什么。
We're saying that, if I'm a node U, and I'm starting at time T.
我们是说，如果我是节点U，并且我是从时间T开始。
AUDIENCE: Ya, so that's like one piece of paper.
听众：是的，那就像一张纸。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
I'm going to go on the road, right?
我要上路了吧？
I'm going to go on the road from U to V.
我要走从U到V的路。
So where am I going to arrive?
那我要去哪里呢？
AUDIENCE: There at V at some time plus that.
听众：有时V在那儿。
PROFESSOR: Now we have to figure out what time
教授：现在我们必须弄清楚什么时间
we're going to arrive at.
我们要到达。
The time that we arrive at is the original time,
我们到达的时间是原始时间，
plus whatever time I'm going to spend on the road.
再加上我要花在路上的任何时间。
What's the time I spend on the road?
我在路上花什么时间？
It's not constant because I have that timetable that
它不是恒定的，因为我有时间表
includes traffic.
包括流量。
So this is what this tells me.
这就是告诉我的。
This is what this big, ugly formula is all about.
这就是这个大而丑陋的公式的全部含义。
It says the timetable for this edge assuming
它说，这一优势的时间表假设
you start at time T. That's all there is.
您从时间T开始。仅此而已。
Nothing else.
没有其他的。
AUDIENCE: What's the second line, then?
观众：那第二行是什么？
PROFESSOR: So the second line is waiting.
教授：第二行正在等待。
So if I don't have this then I'm constrained
所以，如果我没有这个，那我就会被束缚
in that I have to drive all the time.
因为我必须一直开车。
I go from here to Amherst, then I
我从这里去阿默斯特，然后我
have to go from Amherst to somewhere else, and keep going,
必须从阿默斯特去其他地方，然后继续前进，
keep going, keep going.
继续前进，继续前进。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, this is where I wait for a minute.
教授：是的，这是我等一下。
If I wait for a minute, I don't consume any fuel
如果我等一下，我不会消耗任何燃料
and I go from time T to time T plus 1.
我从时间T到时间T加1。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: Does this make sense?
教授：这有意义吗？
Do we want to analyze the running time for this really
我们是否真的要分析运行时间
quickly?
很快？
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: How many edges?
教授：几条边？
AUDIENCE: E times M?
听众：E乘以M？
PROFESSOR: OK, let's do vertices because vertices is quick.
教授：好的，因为顶点很快，所以我们来做顶点。
AUDIENCE: V times M?
听众：V乘以M？
PROFESSOR: So, edges is, you're saying, V times M?
教授：那么，边就是V乘M？
Almost.
几乎。
AUDIENCE: Pause there.
听众：在那儿停一下。
PROFESSOR: So there's a pause, right?
教授：所以有一个停顿吧？
How many pause edges do I have?
我有几个停顿边缘？
AUDIENCE: V-- M.
听众：V– M.
PROFESSOR: This is how many vertices?
教授：这是多少个顶点？
This is how many edges?
这边有几条？
Plug this into which algorithm, Dijkstra or Bellam-Ford?
将其插入Dijkstra或Bellam-Ford哪种算法中？
AUDIENCE: Dijkstra.
听众：Dijkstra。
PROFESSOR: Done!
教授：做完了！
Yay, we solved the hard problem.
是的，我们解决了难题。
AUDIENCE: How do you ensure that the time's right?
听众：您如何确保时间合适？
Do you have to go through and see if there's a path?
您是否必须检查一下是否有路径？
PROFESSOR: How do we read the solution?
教授：我们如何阅读解决方案？
That's good.
那很好。
That's a good question.
这是个好问题。
I like that.
我喜欢。
So, we're going to have M vertices of the destination.
因此，我们将拥有目标的M个顶点。
Alright?
好的？
Let's see how they're going to look like.
让我们看看它们的外观。
First off, if you start at 8:00 AM,
首先，如果您从8:00 AM开始，
maybe you're not going to make it to New York at 8:01 AM.
也许您不会在上午8:01到达纽约。
The vertex that says New York at 8:01 AM
在上午8:01说纽约的顶点
is probably going to have a cost of plus infinity.
可能要加上无穷大的成本。
First off the really early times are
首先是真正的早期
going to have a cost of plus infinity.
将要加上无穷大的成本。
Not going to happen.
不会发生。
Then, at some point, the cost is going to become finite.
然后，在某个时候，成本将变得有限。
That's the fastest way you can get from Boston to New York.
从波士顿到纽约，这是最快的方式。
using the least amount of fuel.
使用最少的燃料。
So the cost that you have there is the answer to our problem.
因此，您所付出的代价就是解决我们问题的答案。
AUDIENCE: So basically, when you get there you
观众：所以基本上，当您到达那里时，
have to enter it through all M.
必须通过所有M输入
PROFESSOR: All M vertices that correspond to the destination.
教授：对应于目的地的所有M个顶点。
The costs are going to look like this.
费用将看起来像这样。
They're going to be infinity, infinity, infinity all the way
它们将一直无穷大，无穷大
up, until some point in here you're
起来，直到这里的某个点
going to have your final answer.
将有您的最终答案。
The cost to get there the fastest--
最快到达那里的成本-
see, you can get there at 3:00 PM.
看，您可以在3:00 PM到达那里。
This is how much fuel you have to spend to get there at 3;00
这是您在3; 00到达那里所需要花费的燃料
PM.
下午。
But, if you're willing to wait until 3:01 PM,
但是，如果您愿意等到下午3:01，
you're going to have the fastest cost you can have for that.
您将为此付出最快的代价。
If you're willing to wait until 3:02,
如果您愿意等到3:02，
you're going to have the answer for that, too.
您也将得到答案。
So here you're going to get the whole trade-off curve of,
所以在这里，您将获得的总折衷曲线，
if you're willing to wait for a few minutes,
如果您愿意等待几分钟，
or if you're willing to wait for an extra hour, how
或者如果您愿意等待一个多小时，如何
much fuel you can save.
您可以节省很多燃料。
So, I think that's cool about your questions.
因此，我认为您的问题很酷。
You had a question, too.
您也有一个问题。
AUDIENCE: Why did we have V times M
听众：为什么我们有V乘以M
in the E prime expression?
在E素数表达式中？
PROFESSOR: First off, we have E times M, right?
教授：首先，我们有E倍M，对不对？
We're good with these.
我们对这些很好。
These are the waiting edges.
这些是等待的边缘。
AUDIENCE: So we are waiting after every minute?
观众：所以我们每分钟都在等待吗？
PROFESSOR: The waiting edges are vertex time
教授：等待的边缘是顶点时间
to vertex time plus 1.
顶点时间加1。
How many vertices?
多少个顶点？
V. How many times?
五，多少次？
AUDIENCE: M.
听众：M.
PROFESSOR: So it's V times M. Because at each minute,
教授：是V乘以M。因为每一分钟，
you can be at a certain city and decide
你可以在某个城市决定
to wait one more minute to stay the same city.
再等一分钟再呆在同一座城市。
OK Does this make sense?
好，这有意义吗？
Thank you guys!
感谢大伙们！
I'm really happy we solved the hard problem!
我真的很高兴我们解决了难题！
That's good.
那很好。